{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In the time since E. coli and Salmonella diverged evolutionarily", "opta": "there has been little change in either genome", "optb": "E. coli has acquired many genes via horizontal transfer", "optc": "E, coli has lost approximately 50% of its genome", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following theory is supported by the genomic sequence of the obligate intracellular parasite Rickettsia prowazekii ?", "opta": "Parasitic bacteria have very large genomes", "optb": "Parasites have a definite genomic sequence similar to viruses", "optc": "Mitochondria have evolved from endosymbiotic bacteria", "optd": "All bacteria evolved from viruses", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The physical nature of genomes is studied under", "opta": "structural genomics", "optb": "comparative genomics", "optc": "proteo genomics", "optd": "functional genomics", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The species of bacteria, which possesses 250 genes for lipid biosynthesis is", "opta": "M. genitalium", "optb": "M. tuberculosis", "optc": "E. coli", "optd": "H. influenzae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why the bacterium Treponema pallidum is difficult to culture?", "opta": "Because it requires a great deal of water to reproduce", "optb": "Because it is unable to use carbohydrates as an energy source", "optc": "Because it lacks the genes needed for TCA cycle and oxidative phosphorylation", "optd": "Because it requires extremely low temperature at which water freezes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the range of minimum set of genes required for life?", "opta": "50-100 genes", "optb": "250-350 genes", "optc": "1000-1500 genes", "optd": "1500-2000 genes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The flow of genetic material in microbial cells usually takes place from", "opta": "RNA through DNA to proteins", "optb": "proteins through RNA to DNA", "optc": "DNA through RNA to proteins", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used for determining the location of specific genes within the genome?", "opta": "Genomics", "optb": "Annotation", "optc": "Cloning", "optd": "Proteomics", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Proteomics is", "opta": "the study of algal genomes", "optb": "a branch of quantum physics dealing with proteins", "optc": "the study of formation of lipo-protein in animals", "optd": "the study of the entire collection of proteins expressed by an organism", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is concerned with the management and analysis of biological data using computers?", "opta": "Bio-physics", "optb": "Bioinformatics", "optc": "Genomics", "optd": "Biomechanics", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of genomics studies the transcripts and proteins expressed by a genome?", "opta": "Comparative genomics", "optb": "Structural genomics", "optc": "Proteo genomics", "optd": "Functional genomics", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the study of the molecular organization of genomes, their information content and the gene products they encode?", "opta": "Genetics", "optb": "Ergonomics", "optc": "Genomics", "optd": "Bioinformatics", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The word, used for the small solid supports onto which are spotted hundreds of thousands of tiny drops of DNA that can be used to screen gene expression, is", "opta": "southern blot", "optb": "cloning library", "optc": "DNA microarrays", "optd": "northern blot", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organisms has the smallest genome?", "opta": "H. influenzae", "optb": "M. genitalium", "optc": "M. tuberculosis", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Studies of similarities and differences among the genomes of multiple organisms is carried out in", "opta": "comparative genomics", "optb": "proteomics", "optc": "functional genomics", "optd": "structural genomics", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why Deinococcus radiodurans is able to survive massive exposure to radiation?", "opta": "Because it produces a thick shell which acts as a shield from the radiation", "optb": "Because it has unique DNA repair mechanisms", "optc": "Because its cellwall contains radioactive elements", "optd": "Because it has many copies of genes encoding DNA repair", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}